Vitor de Almeida Assuena

Senior Business Analyst working at Loggi, Brazil's logistics unicorn startup. Highly experienced in **data analysis and insights** to address business' pain points. Solid **SQL** and **Python** knowledge for data analysis/modeling and experience with tools like **Power BI, Looker, Kibana, Grafana, DBT and AWS Lambda**.

São Paulo - SP - Brazil Open for Remote positions +55 11 93383-5442 vitorassuena@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/vitorassuena

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Loggi — Senior Business Analyst

JAN 2022 - PRESENT - Unicorn with ~2k employees backed by Softbank, Advent, Microsoft etc.

- Maintain existing KPIs and develop new ones to allow a better understanding of the company's challenges and levers. This is done in 2 fronts:
 - Business: Work closely with different areas to determine the rules of the metric, ensuring everyone is on the same page and the metrics are aligned with the business goals
 - o **Technical:** Mostly using SQL, DBT, LookML (Looker)
- Information management: support the entire Operations BU and make sure every level of the company (analysts, managers and VPs) know where to find what they need, with the level of detail they need;
- Develop/maintain a Vehicle Simulator to determine the quantity/type
 of vehicles needed each day for each route. Developed in Python and
 used weekly by the entire Vehicle Planning team;
- Integrated a spreadsheet to an API to allow for mass route creation/customization in our vehicle planning system developed internally. This saves 20h/week and over BRL 400k/month;
- Pilot project: Classification model (Machine Learning) to help establish the most important input metrics for our company's quality KPIs.

Astra — Projects Analyst

JAN 2021 - DEC 2021 - Manufacturing company with over 1k employees and BRL 1b revenue

- Promote a data-driven environment on a daily basis;
- In-depth analysis of our quality internal audit to prioritize that year's maintenance/revamp projects.

Coca-Cola FEMSA — Supply Chain Intern

JAN 2019 - DEC 2020 - Largest beverage bottling plant in the World

- Develop Power BI dashboards used daily by hundreds of employees in the Manufacturing BU: loss rate, freight damage, projects' status;
- Lead continuous improvement projects with the main goal of addressing the top issues found through the dashboards analysis.

EDUCATION

MBA in Data Science and Analytics, 2024 (in progress) Universidade de São Paulo (USP)

Materials Engineering - Universidade Federal de Itajubá (UNIFEI)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Developed a Streamlit app used by the entire company to track our semester goals and achievements;
- Public recognition of my work in the Operations Sync with the entire Ops BU.

HARD SKILLS

Data Viz: Power BI, Looker, Grafana, Kibana, Tableau, Python

Data Analytics: Python, SQL, PyCaret/Scikit-Learn (Machine Learning)

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent TOEFL ITP: 657 of 677 (97%)

Spanish - Intermediate

Portuguese - Native

COURSES

SQL for Data Analysis DataCamp

Python for Data Science Alura

Six Sigma Green Belt-CADES